Register of the Julius Epstein Papers, 1939-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE. (Boxes 1-86.)
  - United Nations Organization (Box 72)
    - Handbooks, 2 folders)
    - Headquarters Commission Report, 1946, 3 folders) (Box 74)
    - High Commissioner for Refugees
    - Human rights and genocide
    - Information Office
    - International Court of Justice. See Charter
    - International Health Conference
    - Journal of the United Nations
    - Journal of the United Nations, 2 folders) (Box 75)
    - Korea Report, 1950
    - Missions and Delegations, Summer 1951
    - Peoples and Countries, The United Nations
    - Photographs
    - Photographs (Box 76)
    - Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA) (Box 77)
      - General
      - Official documents, 9 folders)
      - And the International Refugee Organization (IRO)
      - In Yugoslavia
    - Reports on public information
    - Rules of procedure
    - Security Council. See also Charter
      - London session, 1946, 2 folders)
      - New York session, 1946, 2 folders) (Box 78)
      - Organizational papers
      - Subcommittee on Spain
    - Structure
    - Today and Tomorrow, The United Nations
    - Uniting for Peace Resolution
    - Weekly Bulletin
  - United States of America
    - Aid to Tito
    - Air Force (vs. U.S.S.R. Air Force)
    - Around the world
    - Budget trend
    - Vs. Communist Party
    - Communist round-up
    - Defense agreements
    - Foreign policy
      - General
      - 1933-1941
    - Government
      - Against Stalin's dictatorship
      - Against Stalin's practices
      - Against U.S.S.R. (official documents)
      - Recognizes Soviet theft of Baltic States
      - White Book
    - Governors
    - Governors, Senators, and Representatives
    - And Great Britain (coordination) (Box 79)
    - And Greece (military bases agreement)
    - Immigration quotas
    - Labor Unions
    - Navy
    - Vs. Russia (Stokes' series)
    - Senators-81st Congress
    - Stalin, Note to, September 27, 1948
    - And Spain (military bases agreement), 2 folders)
    - Taxes, 1946
    - Universities and colleges
    - And U.S.S.R.
      - Agreement, June 1942
      - Agreement on exchange, January 1958
      - Trade
      - War Information Office
      - War losses
      - War production, 2 folders)
  - United Yugoslav Relief Fund of America
  - Unsettled European problems
  - Uruguay
  - U.S.S.R.
    - General
    - Constitution
    - Map
    - Politics' special issue, 2 folders)
    - Railroad debts
    - Religion, 1963
    - Trading
  - Utley, Freda
  - Valera, Eamon de, 2 folders)
  - Valery, Paul
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H.
    - General
    - Senators' reply to his plan
  - Vansittart, Robert Gilbert, Lord
    - General
    - Kordt affidavit
    - House of Lords speeches
  - Varga, Eugen (Box 80)
  - The Vatican
  - Vayo, J. Alvarez del
  - Verber, Otto. See Ponger, Kurt L.
  - Vereinswegweiser 1944-1945
  - Die Vereinswelt, 1948
  - Victor, Walter, 2 folders)
  - Viereck, George Sylvester
  - Viereck, Peter
  - Vietnam, South (putsch)
  - Villar, Henri
  - Vinnitsa massacre
  - Vinson, Fred M.
    - Incident (regarding 'mission' to the Soviet Union)
    - Opinion on Communist Party
  - Vishinsky, Andrei Y.
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Illness, 1949
    - Interview
    - Press conference, September 26, 1947
    - Speeches
      - November 13, 1948 (Howard quotation)
      - October 23, 1950 (most hypocritical speech)
  - Visson, Andre, 2 folders)
  - Voice of America
    - General, 4 folders)
    - Bad language examples
    - Kohler's white-wash
    - McCarthy and others, 1954
    - McCarthy's investigation, 1953 and 1954
    - Minimizing Katyn investigation
    - Official 'representation'
    - Offical white-wash, 2 folders)
    - Polish American Journal article
    - Program (bi-monthtly)
    - Scranton's series
    - Under Streibert
  - Voigt, F. A.
    - General
    - "Report on the Germans"
  - "Volksecho" (Box 81)
  - Volkspolizei
  - Voznesensky, Nikolai A.
  - Wake Island document
  - Walcher, Fred
  - Waldman, Louis
  - The Waldorf-Astoria
  - Waldrop, Frank C.
  - Wall Street
  - Wallace, DeWitt
  - Wallace, Henry A.
    - General
    - Platform (in comparison with the communists')
    - Report on China, 2 folders)
  - Wallenberg, Ernst
  - Wallenberg, Hans
    - Lasky's letter (concerning J. E.'s article in the New Leader)
    - J. E.'s answer to Lasky
    - Libel suit
    - Material, 2 folders)
    - Die neue Zeitung. Includes "The Case of Hans Wallenberg and the Voice of America: A Reply to Melvin J. Lasky" by J. E.
      - General
      - Material
      - Photostats
    - Testimony before the McCarthy subcommittee
    - Transcript of hearing
    - White-wash
      - General
      - Communist press
  - Wallenberg, Raoul
  - War (Box 82)
    - And peace aims of United Nations leaders, 2 folders)
    - Costs
      - General
      - For the Russians
    - Crimes
      - General
      - Commission
      - Committee Report and Jackson statement
    - Criminal trials, World War II
    - Losses
      - General
      - Lemley statistics
    - With Russia
  - Warburg, Eric M.
  - Warburg, James
  - Warner (Yalta)
  - Warsaw
    - Battle of
    - Ghetto
    - Pact meeting, March 1961
  - Washington
    - Mess
    - News
    - Scandals (Look article)
  - Watkins amendment (to the McCarran-Walter Act)
  - Wavell, Archibald P., Sir
  - Webb, James E. (speech on foreign policy techique)
  - Wedemeyer, A. C.
    - General
    - On Service, Emmerson, etc.
    - Report on Korea, 2 folders)
  - Weekly Review of the New York Times, 1942-1945, 5 folders) (Box 83)
  - My Weekly Reader
  - Weizsacker, Ernst von
    - General
    - Affidavits for
    - Sentence and minority opinion, 3 folders)
  - Welch, Robert
  - Welcome to deserters
  - Welles, Sumner
    - Addresses
    - On him
  - Wels, Otto
  - Die Welt
  - Wennerstrom, Stig (Box 84)
  - Werfel, Franz
  - Werner, Max
    - General
    - Obituaries
  - Westchester debutantes' families
  - Weyman, Stanley Clifford (impostor)
  - Wheeler, Burton K.
  - White, Harry Dexter
    - Brownell expose
    - Case, 4 folders)
    - Life story
    - Memoranda
  - White House Conference on Refugees
  - White Paper
    - On China
    - On Korea
  - White, William L.
  - "Why You Buy Books that Sell Communism"
  - Wick, James L.
  - Wiecher, Ernst
  - Wiegard, Karl H. von
  - Wilhelm II
  - Willkie, Wendell L., 2 folders)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 2 folders)
  - "Win the Peace" Committee
  - Winchell, Walter
    - General, 2 folders)
    - "Blueprint for Disaster"
    - Look applauds him
    - On Truman's administration
  - Windsor, Duke of
  - Winkler, Ernst
  - Wirth, Dr.
  - Wise, Stephen S., Rabbi
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Obituaries
  - Witch craft. See cannibalism
  - Wittfogel, Karl August, 2 folders) (Box 85)
  - Wohl, Paul, 2 folders)
  - Woltman, Frederick
  - Wolverton, Charles A.
  - The Worker
  - World Affairs Manual
  - World armament
    - General
    - New York Times Survey
  - World communism
    - General
    - Bibliography
    - Bolton's study on China
    - Personalities
    - Strategy and tactics
  - "World Congress of Partisans of Peace"
  - World Council of Churches
  - World Court
  - World economic conditions, 1948
  - World Files
  - World Federation of Trade Unions (W.F.T.U.)
  - World history
  - World Jewish Congress
    - General
    - Fellow travelers
    - Information Bulletin
  - World populations
  - World Report, 2 folders)
  - World security documents
  - World War I (Baldwin)
  - World War III
    - General
    - Life story
    - Outbreak in Korea?
    - Outbreak in Korea? (Box 86)
  - Writer's Guide
  - Writers' War Board
  - Wszelaki, Jan
  - Wuolijoki, Hella (on her)
  - Yalta
    - Conference
    - Papers (New York Times, March 17, 1955)
  - Yugoslavia
    - Federal Republic
    - In the American press
  - Young & Rubicam, Inc.
  - Zacharias, Ellis, 2 folders)
  - Zanzibar
  - Zaslavsky, David
  - Zenzinov, Vladimir
  - Zhukov, Marshal
  - Zimmermann Note
  - Zionism
  - Zychon, Jan
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS. (Boxes 87-106.)
  Speeches, articles, statements, and other writings by Julius Epstein, arranged alphabetically by title
  - Adenauer, Konrad (about a private conversation with foreign officials) (Box 87)
  - "The Alaska Plan"
  - "Amerikanische Aussenpolitik und der dritte Weltkrieg" (American foreign policy and the third world war)
  - "Atomwaffenteste, die Wahrheit Uber" (the truth about atomic weapons test)
  - "Der Aufbruch Africas" (the starting point of Africa)
  - "Bang-Jensen, Murder by Protocol"
  - "The Bang-Jensen Tragedy"
  - "Zur Tragodie Bang-Jensens" (the Bang-Jensen tragedy)
  - "Beitritt Bonns zur Volkermord-Konvention" (Bonn's accession to the Genocide Convention)
  - "Blueprints for Nazi Conquest..."
  - Broadcast editorial reports
  - Buber-Neumann, Margarete (about her book "Als Gefangene bei Hitler und Stalin" - as a prisoner of Hitler and Stalin)
  - "Churchill in Potsdam"
  - "The Comintern at Work"
  - Congressional Record
    - January 25, 1946: "The Treaties Stalin Broke"
    - February 7, 1949: "The Two Voices of Soviet Russian Policy..."
    - April 7, 1949: "Communist Words vs. Communist Teaching"
    - May 16, 1950: "Russia and Alaska Statehood"
    - December 11, 1950: "Katyn and The Voice of America"
    - May 1, 1951: "The Mysteries of the Van Vliet Report", 3 folders) (Box 88)
    - February 29, 1952: "Win over the Communists"
    - March 12, 1952: "Churchill Mum on Katyn"
    - May 16, 1951: "Katyn and The Voice of America", 3 folders) (Box 89)
    - April 16, 1953: "A Test for Malenkov", 2 folders)
    - July 16, 1953: Syngman Rhee's letter to W. R. Hearst (Box 90)
    - January 11, 1954: Berlin editors fight U.S. subsidized paper
    - January 10, 1955: "How We Served as Partners in a Purge"
    - March 16, 1955: "Will Congress Repudiate Forced Repatriation?"
    - April 20, 1955: "F.D.R. Says Yalta Papers Fail to Relate Whole Story"
    - June 1, 1955: "Dulles Releases Test of Missing Dipl. Note" (Grew Note)
    - January 5, 1956: "An American Crime"
    - January 5, 1956: "An American Crime"
    - February 1, 1956: "Forced Repatriation", 2 folders) (Box 91)
    - March 27, 1956: "Refugee Blackmail"
    - July 6, 1956: "The United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees"
    - July 16 and 17, 1956: Letter to Pravda - Katyn, 2 folders)
    - January 14 and 23, 1957: Katz-Suchy interview, 4 folders)
    - Feb. 18, 1958: Forced repatriation of political refugees (Box 92)
    - March 6, 1958: U.S.-U.S.S.R. agreement on cultural exchanges, 2 folders)
    - May 8, 1958: "Proof Germany Financed Lenin", 3 folders)
    - May 8, 1958: "Proof Germany Financed Lenin" (Box 93)
    - January 15, 1959: Anastas Mikoyan's visit
    - March 18, 1959: "Not an Inch"
    - April 20, 1959: "Soviet Stand on Germany"
    - June 29, 1959: "Remarks Originally Intended to Be Made at the White House Conference on Refugees"
    - September 23, 1970: "Operation Keelhaul"
  - "Creating Turmoil"
  - "Dean, Vera Micheles, The Case Against"
  - "Dean, Vera Micheles, The Case Against", 2 folders) (Box 94)
  - "Profile of Vera Micheles Dean: A Split Personality, Political Version"
  - "Lettre du General Denikine au General Eisenhower" (Denikin's letter to Eisenhower)
  - "Did General Bissell Perjure Himself in Katyn Forest Massacre Probe?"
    - Part 1
    - Part 2
    - Photostats
  - DIMITAG releases
  - Draft resolution on Germany
  - Dusseldorfer Nachrichten
  - Earle and Canaris story, "Kein Antwort von Prasident Roosevelt" (No answer from President Roosevelt)
  - Facts (letter to the editor)
  - "F.D.R. Was Warned Before He Recognized Soviet"
  - Fechteler Paper (NANA release)
  - "Finnish Jews during the War", 2 folders)
  - Finnish-Soviet Pact (letter to the editor of the Washington Post) (Box 95)
  - Forced repatriation of Soviet prisoners of war
    - List of articles dealing with forced repatriation
    - Articles, 12 folders)
    - Articles, 12 folders) (Box 96)
  - Foreign Policy Association, "Fight in FPA Hits New Peak. Alfred Kohlberg Quits as Active Member"
  - "Our Foreign Policy and the Third World War", 2 folders)
  - "Geheime Dokumente von Potsdam" (secret documents of Potsdam)
  - Genocide Convention and Bonn, 3 folders)
  - "German Plans for Attack upon the United States" (Box 97)
  - "German-Ukranian Operations during World War I", 2 folders)
  - Hammarskjold interview, 3 folders)
  - "Handbook on Communism"
  - "Harriman warnte vor der Austreibung" (Harriman warned about the expulsion of millions of Germans from the territories East of the Oder-Neisse line and from Czechoslovakia)
  - Heute
  - "Hyde Park Files"
  - Industriekurier
  - Industriekurier (Box 98)
  - "Is there Another Germany?"
  - Katanga (interview with Tschombe's representative in the U.S.
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940
    - Articles, 14 folders)
    - Articles, 2 folders) (Box 99)
    - Hearings
  - "Das Katyn von Korea" (Korea's Katyn)
  - Katz-Suchy interview
  - "Koexistenz, Die Wahrheit uber die" (the truth about coexistence)
  - Kolnische Rundschau
  - Kultura
  - "Lack of Leadership"
  - Lemkin interview, 4 folders)
  - "Lenins deutsche Millionen" (Lenin's German millions)
  - "Lenin und die Kaisers Millionen" (Lenin and the Kaiser's millions)
  - "Proof Germany Financed Russia"
  - Letters to the editor
    - General
    - On Hans Wallenberg
  - "Mikoyan, der Meisterspion, kommt" (Mikoyan, the master spy, is coming) (Box 100)
  - Mixed supporting documents
  - "The Mysteries of the Van Vliet Report", 2 folders)
  - NANA releases
    - Klimow interview
    - "Naval expert..."
    - Olshanski-Burdenko
  - Neue Zeitung - Berlin edition, 2 folders)
  - "Our Foreign Policy and the Third World War"
  - The Office of War Information and the Voice of America, 5 folders)
  - "Dr. Paul's Flight"
  - Photo offset reprints of articles, 9 folders)
  - Possony, Stefan (Box 101)
    - Chicago lecture
    - Interview
  - Potsdam, in Rheinischer Merkur
    - Documents
    - Series
  - Potsdam Papers
  - "Aus den Potsdamer Dokumenten" (out of the Potsdam documents)
  - Radio Free Europe, 2 folders)
  - Rapacki interview
  - Raskolnikov, F., "An Open Letter to Stalin"
  - Re-defection
  - Religious News Service
  - Rhee (on Korea sell-out)
  - Rheinischer Merkur, 3 folders)
  - "Russia and Alaska Statehood"
  - Schlabrendorff conference
  - Seeckt Papers, 4 folders) (Box 102)
  - Soviet cosmonauts
  - Spadea syndicate
    - Clippings
    - Releases
  - Der Spiegel, 2 folders)
  - Staatszeitung und Herold, New York
  - "Stalin's Aid to Hitler"
  - "Stalin-Benes Secret Treaties..."
  - Stalin-Hitler secret treaties
  - Stalin-Hitler secret treaties, 4 folders) (Box 103)
  - Stalin's broken treaties, 4 folders)
  - Stalin's New German Army, 9 folders)
  - Stalin's slave labor in Germany
  - "Stalin's Thwarted Turkish War", 5 folders) (Box 104)
  - Stalin's two voices, 5 folders)
  - "Stalin on War"
  - Statement before the Senate's Appropriations Committee (Box 105)
  - "Stevenson von Bundy Zuruckgepfiffen" (Stevenson called back by Bundy)
  - "Stimmen der Warner in der Geschichte" (voices of warning in history)
  - Stuttgarter Nachrichten
  - Suddeutsche Zeitung
  - Sudetendeutsche Zeitung
  - Tagesspiegel
  - Test ban
  - "A Test for Malenkov", 2 folders)
  - "They Knew They Were Lost"
  - "Triumph und Tragodie der VN" (triumph and tragedy of the UN)
  - Truman, Letter to
  - Tuapse crew accosted
  - "Ullrich, Die Tat des Dr. Johannes" (Box 106)
  - "Van Vliet Report, The Mysteries of"
  - "Verschworung von Teheran" (the conspiracy of Teheran)
  - Vishinsky, Letter to
  - Wallenberg, Hans
    - "The Voice of America and Hans Wallenberg"
    - Norbert Muhlen's letter about J. E.'s article
  - "Warum lugt Khrushev? (why is Khrushchev lying?)
  - Washington Post
  - "Wer sturzte den letzten Zaren?" (who protected the last tsar?)
  - "Why Did We Yield to the Soviets in Berlin?"
  - "Why Don't We Help Liberate Albania?"
  - "Win over the Communists"
- CORRESPONDENCE. (Boxes 107-113.)
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent
  - Der Abend (Box 107)
  - Abendpost
  - Academie Internationale de Medecine Legale et de Medecine Sociale (International Academy of Legal Medicine and of Social Medicine)
  - Adler, Arthur M.
  - Air Force Historical Foundation
  - Aktuell
  - Alaska statement (sent to...)
  - America
  - American Anti-Communist League
  - American Broadcasting Company
  - American Cable & Radio Corporation
  - American Council of Voluntary Agencies, Inc.
  - American Express Company
  - American Jewish Committee
  - American Jewish Conference
  - American Mercury
  - American Publishers
  - American Veterans Committee
  - ANETA News Agency
  - The Answer Man
  - Arbeitsgemeinschaft der Russland-Deutsche (Community of Russia-German settlers, Stuttgart)
  - Arens, Richard
  - Arlet, Wieslaw
  - Aschenauer, Rudolf
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations, 2 folders)
  - The Associated Polish Home
  - Associated Press
  - The Atlantic Monthly
  - Aussenpolitik
  - Baarslag, Karl
  - Badisches Tagblatt
  - Bang-Jensen, Povl
    - Article by J. E. (sent to...)
    - Case (Washington crop, duplicates)
    - Clippings
    - Correspondence of J. E. with
      - Mrs. Bang-Jensen
      - Riess, Curt, 3 folders)
  - Barkin, Milton
  - Barrett, Edward W.
  - Barth, Otto-Wilhelm - Speech
  - Basler Arbeiterzeitung
  - Basler Nachrichten
  - Becher, Walter, Dr.
  - Beck, Werner, Dr. (Box 108)
  - Beclay, John J.
  - Beer, Max, Dr.
  - Beigel, Grete
  - Belorussian Central Administration
  - Benton, William
  - Berndorff, H. R.
  - Besterman, Walter
  - Bevin, Ernest
  - Bielinski, Viktor
  - Bogolepov, Igor
  - Bonn, Auswartiges Amt (Foreign office)
  - Borin, V. L.
  - Botschaft der Bundesrepublik Deutschland (Embassy of the Federal Republic of Germany, Washington, D.C.)
  - Brahm, Heinz
  - Brandt, Willy
  - Brentano, Heinrich von, Dr.
  - Bridges, Styles
  - British Embassy, Washington, D.C.
  - "Broadcast Editorial Reports", 2 folders)
  - Broadman, Joseph, Dr.
  - Bromberg, Sidney S.
  - Brown, Constantine
  - Brown, Curtis, Ltd.
  - Bureda, Botho E. K., Professor
  - Bunche, Ralph, 2 folders)
  - Bundesarchiv, Koblenz (Federal archives)
  - Burns, Rita A.
  - Busbey, Fred E.
  - Caballero, Gimenez Ernesto
  - Cadogan, Alexander, Sir
  - Cannon, Clarence
  - Cardozo, Michael. H., Professor
  - Carter, Bull and McNulty
  - Casement, Roger, Sir (J. E.'s correspondence with various people regarding his project on Sir Roger Casement's case)
  - Caderberg, Ivar W.
  - Christian Science Monitor
  - Chubaty, Nicholas, Professor
  - Cianflone, Ann
  - Cohen, Benjamin
  - Cole, Felix
  - Coman, John B.
  - Committee for a Free Lithuania
  - Committee for Constitutional Government, Inc.
  - Committee on Pan-American Policy
  - Committee on Un-American Activities
  - Coordinator of Information, Mr. Wilson
  - Council Against Communist Aggression
  - Crain, Kenneth C., Mrs.
  - Czas
  - Daily News
  - Daily Worker
  - Dayton, Paul
  - Delaney, E. L.
  - Dende, Henry J.
  - Dende, Leopold
  - Denikin, Mrs.
  - Department of Defense, U.S.
  - Department of Justice, U.S., 2 folders)
  - Department of National Defence, Canada
  - Detroiter Abend-Post
  - Deutsche Bibliothek, Frankfurt am Main (German library)
  - Deutsche Rundschau, Rudolf Pechel
  - Deutschmann, Rudi
  - DIMITAG
  - Dobriansky, Lev E. (Box 109)
  - Dolbeare, Frederic R.
  - Dondero, George A.
  - Donovan, William J.
  - Doyle, Clyde
  - Draft Resolution on Germany
  - Dworshak, Henry C.
  - Easton, Edward R., Jr.
  - Eckhardt, Tibor von, Dr.
  - Economic Coorperation Administration
  - Editor & Publisher
  - Einstein, Albert
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - Correspondence with, 3 folders)
    - Press conferences, 1960
  - Ellender, Allen J.
  - Epstein, Edward P. D.D.S.
  - Essener Tageszeitung (Fritz Lucke)
  - Europa-Archiv
  - Europa Verlag AG (publishing firm)
  - European Recovery Program Administration
  - The Evening Star
  - Everybody's Publications, Ltd.
  - Executive Services
  - Exhibits
  - Exil et Liberte (exile and freedom)
  - Eye doctor
  - Fabian, Bela, Dr.
  - Facchetti-Guiglia, A., Count
  - Facts Forum News
  - Faulkner, Alex H.
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, New York Office, 2 folders)
  - Feighan, Michael A.
  - Feltrinelli, Giangiacomo
  - Finnish Legation, Washington, D.C. (Box 110)
  - Fischer, George
  - Fisher, Peter Thomas
  - Fitzpatrick, Michael F.
  - Flynn, John T.
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations
  - Forced repatriation (research forms)
  - Foreign Journalists Branch, U.S. Department of State
  - Foreign Policy Association
  - Foreign Publicity Executives
  - Foreign Relations Committee (U.S. Senate)
  - Fort Dix (New Jersey)
  - Fotitsch, Constantin A.
  - Foundation for Economic Education, Inc.
  - Frankfurter neue Presse
  - Franzen, Eric, Dr.
  - "Free Europe" broadcasts
  - Freie Innerschweiz
  - Freie Rundschau, Munich
  - Freund, Gerald
  - Friediger, Mr.
  - Friends of National Russia
  - Fuhrman, Murray, M.D. (Blumbi x-rays, 1953)
  - Fuller, C. Dale
  - Fund for the Republic, Inc.
  - Funk & Wagnalls Company (publishers)
  - Galimbzrti, Oscar, Rev.
  - Gamble, Charles and Associates, Inc.
  - Garside, Edward B.
  - Gasbarra, Felix, Dr.
  - Gazette-Democrat
  - General American Investors Company, Inc.
  - George, Walter F.
  - Gerard, James
  - German Consulate General, New York
  - German Diplomatic Mission, Washington, D.C., 2 folders)
  - German newspapers (Washington crop, 1953)
  - Ghito-Bekessy, Ali
  - Glaser, Ernst
  - Glaser, Inge
  - Glaser, Kurt, 2 folders)
  - Glauber, Richard, Dr.
  - Goldsmith Bros.
  - Gottinger Arbeitskreis and Research Committee, 2 folders)
  - Gottinger Tageblatt
  - Gouzenko, Igor
  - Government Operations Subcommittee
  - Government Printing Office (refund stamps)
  - Greek Legation, Washington, D.C.
  - Green, Andrew W.
  - Green, Montgomery M.
  - Greenfield, Robert Kent, Professor
  - Grew Note article (sent to...)
  - Grimm, Robert
  - Gross, Rebecca F.
  - Grottian, Walter, Dr.
  - Gruning, Mr. (governor of Alaska)
  - Gunther, Blair F.
  - Gunther, Otto
  - Gurster, Eugen
  - Gutheil, Emil, Dr.
  - Gydinski, Joseph C.
  - Hamburger Anzeiger
  - Hamburger Morgenpost
  - Hamburger, Philip
  - Hammarskjold, Dag
  - Hangen, Welles
  - Hannoversche Presse
  - Harper's Magazine
  - Harrigan, William F., M.D.
  - Harris, Newmark & Company
  - The Hartford Courant
  - Harvard University
  - Hayden, Carl
  - Hearst, William Randolph, Jr.
  - Hearst Corporation
  - Heinz, Friedrich Wilhelm (pseud. Horst Falkenhagen)
  - Heitzman, M., Professor
  - Heller, Peter
  - Herre, Heinz Danko (Box 111)
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940
    - Clippings
    - Correspondence with Katyn Archives
    - Memorial
  - Kempner, Robert
  - Kennedy, John F.
  - Khrushchev, Nikita, 2 folders)
  - Kwasniewski, Tadeusz (Box 112)
  - Manuscripts (English)
    - General
    - The Bang-Jensen case, 2 folders)
    - Oration on Bang-Jensen
    - "German-Ukrainian Operations during World War I"
    - "German-Bolshevist Conspiracy"
    - Ghostwritings
    - Letter to Jim Hagerty
    - Letters to the editor, 2 folders)
    - "The Road to Disaster"
  - Mark, George L.
  - Martin, David (Dodd Committee)
  - Marxov, Hedwig
  - Matsch, Franz, Dr.
  - Matuzas, C.
  - Mau, Hermann
  - May, Mark A. (Yale)
  - McArdle, John Philip
  - McCarthy's Famous Steak House
  - McCoy, John
  - McNarney, General
  - McNulty, Iona
  - McVeigh, Margarete
  - Menne, Bernhard (Kristall)
  - Menshikov, Mikhail A.
  - Menth, Herma
  - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer
  - Metropolitan Office Cleaning Corp. (Box 113)
  - Meyer-Dietrich, Helmuth
  - Meyer-Lindenberg, Prof.
  - Mieczyslawska, Aniela
  - Military Government for Germany - U.S. (Colonel H. J. Lemley)
  - Military Tribunal, Nuremberg